http://www.magclearsmines.org/privacy-policy/

What we do
What we do
We find and destroy landmines, cluster munitions and unexploded bombs in places affected by conflict. Since 1989, we have helped over 19 million people in 68 countries rebuild their lives and livelihoods after war.
Discover more
Where we work
Clear landmines and cluster bombs
Advocacy and campaigning
Arms management and destruction
Risk education
How to help
How to help
Whether you want to run a marathon, host a cake sale or get your community group involved, you can make a difference to the lives of people affected by conflict.
Discover more
Raise funds
Make a donation
Leave a legacy
Corporate partnerships
Philanthropy
Other ways to give
Newsletter
Give by cheque or over the phone
MAG Privacy NoticeWe rely on the generosity of thousands of supporters to continue our work. MAG is committed to protecting the data we collect during the course of our work and maintaining the trust of the people we deal with. The aim of this notice is to be transparent with you about what we do with your information in terms of how we collect, manage, use and protect your personal data.This privacy notice (the “MAG Privacy Notice”) applies to all personal information processing activities carried on by the Mines Advisory Group ("MAG").MAG is a data controller in respect of personal information that we process in connection with our business (including the products and services that we provide). In this notice, references to “we”, “us” or “our” are references to MAG.If you have any questions regarding this notice, would like more information or would like to change the way we communicate with you, please contact us at:Email: info@maginternational.orgPhone: 0161 236 4311Post: MAG, Suite 3A, South Central, 11 Peter Street, Manchester, M2 5QRThis notice is subject to change. Please visit this website section periodically in order to keep up to date.What information is collected about me?Personal information may be collected directly from you when you interact with MAG, for example when you make a donation, subscribe to email updates, make a complaint, register as a volunteer, sign up to participate in an event or apply for a job with MAG.Personal information may also be collected indirectly when you interact with third parties with whom we work. For example, if you made a donation or started a fundraising page on a third party website such as Just Giving, Virgin Money Giving, Action Challenge, the Charities Aid Foundation, or if you started a job application through any job board sites and gave them permission to share your information with us. These organisations will have their own privacy policies which you should be aware of before signing up.The information we collect may typically include your name, postal and email addresses, your phone number, tax payer status for Gift Aid purposes, your financial details if you are supporting us with a donation and details of your education/career history if you are applying for a position with MAG. In addition in some circumstances we collect the following:employer details for processing a payroll donationdate of birth, age, and/or gender, where appropriate (e.g. if registering for a challenge eventor for research purposes)medical declaration if participating in a MAG challenge event. This information is only usedfor the purposes of participation in the event and is stored no longer than necessarynationality if applying for an overseas position due to potential visa restrictionsWe do not use cookies to collect this type of information. Along with the personal information you have provided we collect information on your interactions with us, including contact we have with you. We may collect and record any other relevant information you share with us such as your interests, affiliations with community or other groups, your employer or the causes you support.We do not routinely collect sensitive personal information (as defined by data protection regulations) unless there is a clear reason for doing so, such as those listed above.How do you use my information?We collect this information in order to process your requests, enquiries and job applications, as well as to keep in touch with you about our work and how you can support this. Examples include:to provide the information/service/product you have requested or we feel may beinterested into process your donationto claim Gift Aid on your donation, if permittedto share information about our work including campaignsto ask you to financially support MAG through a donation or participation in an eventfor administrative purposes including: information on an event you are participating in,queries about a donation, responding to a complaintto participate in a survey which we occasionally run to help us improve our approach tofundraisingto contact you in your capacity as contact at an organisation e.g. community group,business, trust or foundation, where we have obtained your details from the organisationto better understand your preferences and interests, as detailed below, and to identify newaudiencesto be able to process information about you for normal recruitment purposesas required by law, as detailed belowIf you have provided your email and/or SMS details, we will contact you by these means for marketing purposes where we have your consent to do so. You can withdraw your consent at any time by contacting us.If you have provided your postal address and/or telephone number, we will send you information about our projects and fundraising activities, where we have a legitimate interest, and provide you with information on how to stop this type of communication, unless you have requested no contact in this way.We take steps to keep your information secure, accurate and up to date. We follow payment card industry guidance and use secure sites to transfer information between locations. We aim to protect your information but we cannot guarantee the security of data transmitted to our website and transmission is at the user’s risk.We only process your data where you have given us consent to do so or where there is a clear legitimate interest. And we never sell or swap your data.Data analysis and profilingIn order to contact you in the most appropriate way and with the most relevant information we may conduct analysis of your data and the extent to which you’ve engaged with and responded to previous communications from MAG. As part of this process we sometime use additional external publicly available sources to improve and enhance the information we hold about you. This may include obtaining details of changes of address. To better understand our supporters we may use anonymous information, such as your postcode, to obtain demographic information associated with the area you live through third party suppliers. These activities allows us to use our resources more efficiently. We do not undertake any automated profiling on job applicants.Where we have identified that you may have the ability or affinity to support MAG at a higher level we may use the information we hold on you or information which is publically available, such as internet searches, public databases, media coverage and professional networking sites, to:establish connections to existing MAG supportersdetermine philanthropic associations and interestsresearch your interestsengage with you in a more personalised way.Working with Third PartiesWe use companies to provide services and to process data on our behalf such as printing and posting materials, making telephone calls or processing donations. We only provide these organisations with the information they need for the specific purpose they are carrying out on our behalf. We make sure that your information is handled securely and only stored for as long as necessary, just as if we were handling it ourselves.We do not sell or swap your information for marketing purposes.Legal disclosureIf required by law or regulation we may disclose your information as required, for example to comply with money laundering regulations or to perform the necessary due diligence. We are required to share your information with HMRC for Gift Aid purposes.How long do you keep my information?We will only retain your information for as long as you have an active relationship with us, or are going through a recruitment process, in which case your information will be retained for 6 months. If you cease to have an active relationship with us or request to receive no further contact, we will retain some basic information in order to avoid sending you unwanted materials in the future, for Gift Aid purposes, for financial record keeping and fraud prevention purposes and to ensure that we don’t accidentally duplicate information.What happens with my information if I apply for a job or volunteer?Upon applying to work or volunteer at MAG, we will only use the information you give to us to process your application and to monitor recruitment statistics. The type of information we typically collect during the recruitment process includes name, address, nationality, contact details, qualifications, work history and reference details.All job applications are saved and retained for 6 months. Access to this information is restricted to MAG’s HR team and recruiting managers and is stored securely. If you would like for us to remove your details at any time, please email human.resources@maginternational.org to let us know. When recruiting for a job based in a MAG programme, we will usually need to transfer your applicant information to that country to assess your application. You should be aware that due to the locations that MAG works in, this country is likely to be outside of the European Economic Area. You should be aware that protection for personal information may not be equivalent to the protection provided in the EEA. However, MAG will seek to uphold the same standards of security and respect when processing your data across our organisation. By submitting your personal information to us when applying for a job at MAG, you agree to this transfer, storing and processing at a location outside the EEA.If during the recruitment process we need to disclose your data to persons outside of MAG; for example, when obtaining references or to obtain a disclosure from the Disclosure Barring Service, we will inform you in advance.If you are offered employment or a volunteering opportunity, you will be provided with further information on our data protection standards and with whom we will share your data. This includes MAG HR’s full privacy statement which outlines in more detail what data may be collected from you at the point a job offer is made to you and during your employment with MAG as well as information on how this is used/stored.If you are no longer working or volunteering with us we will keep your details in accordance with our internal data retention standards.What rights do I have?We want to make sure you are aware of your rights in relation to the personal information we process about you. We have summarised those rights below:You have a right to get access to the personal information we hold about you.You have a right to rectification of inaccurate personal information and to update incompletepersonal information.You have a right to request that we delete your personal information.You have a right to request us to restrict the processing of your personal information.You have a right to receive any personal information you provided to us in a portable format.You have a right to object to the processing of your personal information.You have a right to object to direct marketing.Where we rely on your permission to process your personal information, you have a right to withdraw your consent at any time.How to exercise your rightsIf you wish to exercise any of these rights, if you have any queries about how we use your personal information that are not answered here, or if you wish to complain, , please write to us at:MAG, Suite 3A, South Central, 11 Peter Street, Manchester, M2 5QROr email info@maginternational.orgWe aim to acknowledge your request within five working days of receipt and provide a full response without delay and within one month. You can raise a concern or complaint to us by contacting us at the information provided at the top of this page.If you are not happy with how we have handled your concern or complaint or would like to raise an issue directly, you can contact the Office of the Information Commissioner, which oversees the protection of personal data in the UK, or the Fundraising Regulator, which is responsible for overseeing fundraising activities carried out by charities in the UK.This notice was last updated in April 2018MAG is registered with the Fundraising Regulator.MAG is registered as a charitable company in the UK. Company no: 4016409, Charity no: 1083008
Our site uses cookies. By browsing you are agreeing to our use of cookies.
Read our cookie policy
Welcome
Welcome to the MAG International website.
Did you mean to visit MAG America?
Click here
To stay on the current site, close this window
Welcome
Welcome to the MAG America website.
Did you mean to visit MAG International?
Click here
To stay on the current site, close this window
